Alright, welcome back to Rock the JVM's Scala at Lightspeed.
さあ、Rock the JVMのScala at Lightspeedに戻ってきたよ。
I'm Daniel and in this video we will discuss some of the advanced Scala features that you will probably see in real life.
Danielだよ。今回は実際の開発で出会うであろうScalaの上級機能について話していくね。
Alright, so I'm going to go back to the project that we started at the beginning of the series.
じゃあ、シリーズの最初に作ったプロジェクトに戻ろう。
If you're new to this video series, go back to the first video where we set up the initial files.
この動画シリーズを初めて見る人は、最初の動画に戻ってファイルのセットアップをしてね。
Now, specifically for this video, I'm going to create a new Scala application.
さて、今回の動画では新しいScalaアプリケーションを作るよ。
So under the com.rock, the JVM package, I'm going to select new Scala class, I'm going to name this advanced.
com.rocktheJVMパッケージの下で、新しいScalaクラスを選んで、advancedって名前にする。
I'm going to make it an object as before and I'm going to have it extend app so that we can run it on our computer as a standalone application.
前と同じようにobjectにして、Appをextendsすることで、スタンドアロンのアプリケーションとして実行できるようにするよ。
You can also test this code yourself.
みんなも自分でこのコードを試してみてね。
Now, the very first thing that I want to show you in this suite of advanced Scala features is lazy evaluation.
さて、この上級Scala機能の中でまず最初に見せたいのが、遅延評価（lazy evaluation）だよ。
Lazy evaluation means that an expression is not evaluated until it's first used.
遅延評価っていうのは、式が最初に使われるまで評価されないっていう仕組みなんだ。
Let me give you an example.
例を見せるね。
If I define a lazy val, let's call this a lazy value, and I give it a value of 2.
lazy valを定義して、名前をlazyValueとしよう。で、値として2を代入する。
The number 2 is not associated to a lazy value until it's used for the first time.
この数値2は、lazyValueが最初に使われるまで関連付けられないんだ。
And this can be illustrated with a side effect.
これは副作用を使うと分かりやすいよ。
So I'm going to create a lazy val, let's call this lazy value with side effect.
lazy valを作って、名前をlazyValueWithSideEffectとしよう。
As being, and I'm going to open and close some curly braces, this meaning I'm going to set up a code block.
値として、波括弧を開いて閉じる、つまりコードブロックを書くよ。
And as you learned before, a code block is an expression whose value is the value of the last expression.
前に学んだように、コードブロックっていうのは、最後の式の値がそのブロック全体の値になる式だよね。
So I'm going to print line, for example, I am so very lazy.
じゃあprintlnで、例えば「I am so very lazy」って出力するようにして。
And at the end, I'm going to return the value 42 or 43 or something like that, a value.
最後に、42とか43とか、何か値を返すようにする。
Now, as you learned at the beginning of the series, this being a code block has the value of 43 because it's the last expression to be evaluated.
シリーズの最初で学んだように、これはコードブロックだから、最後に評価される式である43が値になるんだ。
Now, if I run this application as a standalone application, nothing will be actually printed to the console, as you can see over here, except this IDE related stuff.
さて、このアプリケーションをスタンドアロンで実行すると、コンソールには何も表示されないんだ。ここに見えるIDEの表示以外はね。
If I take out the lazy modifier, if I run this application, I'm going to see I am so very lazy.
lazyの修飾子を外して実行すると、「I am so very lazy」が表示されるよ。
That is because this code block was evaluated and it was attributed to the lazy value with side effect name.
それは、このコードブロックが評価されて、lazyValueWithSideEffectに値が関連付けられたからだね。
Now, the lazy value is evaluated when it's first used.
lazy valは最初に使われたときに評価されるんだ。
So if I define a small value, let's call this eager value, as lazy value with side effect plus one, even though I'm not printing something out to the console myself,
だから、eagerValueっていうvalを、lazyValueWithSideEffect + 1として定義すると、自分ではprintlnしてないのに、
because I'm using lazy value with side effect for the first time, this code block will actually get evaluated.
lazyValueWithSideEffectが初めて使われるから、このコードブロックが実際に評価されるんだ。
So if I run this application, I'm still going to see I am so very lazy.
アプリケーションを実行すると、やっぱり「I am so very lazy」が表示されるよ。
That is because lazy value with side effect was evaluated because it was used here in this other value.
lazyValueWithSideEffectがこの別のvalの中で使われたから、評価されたんだね。
So I hope this makes sense.
ここまでは分かるかな。
Lazy evaluation is useful in infinite collections and in some more rare use cases.
遅延評価は無限コレクションとか、あとはちょっとレアなユースケースで役に立つよ。
The second advanced bit that I'm going to show you is, let's call them pseudo collections.
次に見せる上級機能は、擬似コレクションと呼ぼう。
Although they are not collections, they are their own types, but you can think of them as collections.
正確にはコレクションじゃなくて、それぞれ独自の型なんだけど、コレクションのように考えることができるんだ。
And in particular, I'm referring to the option type and the try type.
具体的にはOptionとTryのことだよ。
Let's call this pseudo collections in between air quotes so that we understand that option and try are their own types.
OptionとTryはそれぞれ独自の型だから、「擬似コレクション」ってカギ括弧付きで呼ぶことにしよう。
They're not collections themselves.
コレクションそのものではないからね。
What do I mean by that?
どういうことかっていうと、
Option and try are very useful in some use cases in large code bases when you have unsafe methods.
OptionとTryは、大きなコードベースで安全でないメソッドがあるときにすごく便利なんだ。
Let me define an unsafe method.
安全でないメソッドを定義してみよう。
Let's call this method which can return null.
名前はmethodWhichCanReturnNullにする。
Taking null arguments and we declare that this method returns a string.
引数なしで、戻り値の型はStringと宣言する。
And it might return a string or it might return null.
でも、Stringが返るかもしれないし、nullが返るかもしれない。
Let's say it returns a string.
今回はStringを返すとしよう。
Say hello, Scala.
「hello, Scala」っていう文字列ね。
This is a valid string, but in large code bases when you don't have the time or you actually cannot read the implementation of a method,
これは有効な文字列だけど、大きなコードベースでは、メソッドの実装を読む時間がなかったり、そもそも読めなかったりするよね。
all you can do is hope that you will get an actual string.
実際にStringが返ってくることを祈るしかないわけだ。
To guard yourself against nulls, you would have to do if method which can return null is actually equal to null.
nullに対して防御するには、methodWhichCanReturnNullがnullかどうかをifでチェックする必要がある。
And then you can do some defensive code against null, which is what we normally do in other languages like C++ or Java,
そしてnullに対する防御コードを書く。C++やJavaでは普通にやることだよね。
because null pointer exceptions or segmentation faults can actually wreak havoc through our code.
NullPointerExceptionやセグメンテーションフォルトはコードを壊滅させかねないからね。
But in Scala, we don't have to do that if we use the option type.
でもScalaでは、Option型を使えばそんなことしなくていいんだ。
So let me give you an example.
例を見せるね。
Let's define an option as option from Scala.
ScalaのOptionを定義しよう。
So option applied to method which can return null.
Option(methodWhichCanReturnNull)という形で適用する。
You can think of an option as a kind of like a collection of one element at most.
Optionは、最大で1つの要素を持つコレクションのようなものだと思ってほしい。
So a collection between air quotes which contains at most one element.
つまり、カギ括弧付きの「コレクション」で、最大1つの要素を含むんだ。
If this method returns a valid value, then this collection, so to speak, contains the value inside.
メソッドが有効な値を返した場合、この「コレクション」の中にその値が入る。
So this will be a sum with hello Scala.
この場合は「hello, Scala」が入ったSomeになるよ。
This is the subtype of the option abstract type.
SomeはOption抽象型のサブタイプだね。
If the method which can return null actually returns null, the value here will be none.
もしmethodWhichCanReturnNullが実際にnullを返したら、値はNoneになる。
So sum with a value or none, which is a singleton object.
つまり、値を持つSomeか、シングルトンオブジェクトであるNoneかのどちらかだ。
None means the equivalent of null, except this is a regular value.
Noneはnullと同等の意味だけど、これは普通の値なんだ。
So there's no risk in accessing illegal members or methods.
だから不正なメンバーやメソッドにアクセスするリスクがないよ。
If you know pattern matching from the previous video, you will be able to understand the following code.
前の動画でpattern matchingを学んだなら、次のコードは理解できるはずだよ。
We can say val, let's call this string processing or string processed or something like that.
valを定義して、名前はstringProcessingとかstringProcessedとか、そんな感じにしよう。
You can pattern match this option.
このOptionに対してpattern matchができるんだ。
So you can say an option match and you can add a case for some string and you can return whatever you like.
anOption matchと書いて、Some(string)のcaseを追加して、好きなものを返せる。
For example, I have obtained a valid string and you can inject the string inside.
例えば「I have obtained a valid string」と書いて、中にstringを埋め込むことができる。
Or in case you get a none, which is the singleton object, of course, deriving from option, you can say I obtained nothing.
あるいはNoneのcaseでは、Optionから派生したシングルトンオブジェクトだけど、「I obtained nothing」と返せる。
So notice that there are no null checks that you would normally add for defensive code in other programming languages.
注目してほしいのは、他のプログラミング言語で防御コードとして書くようなnullチェックがないってことだよ。
So all you have to do is to wrap your unsafe code in an option and then do a pattern match on it.
やることは、安全でないコードをOptionでラップして、pattern matchするだけなんだ。
Or you can operate with options like you would on collections with map, flat map and filter.
あるいは、コレクションと同じようにmap、flatMap、filterを使ってOptionを操作できる。
If you remember these functions, we discussed them on lists earlier in the video series.
これらの関数は覚えてるかな。シリーズの前の方でListについて話したときに出てきたよね。
So this was option which guards against needing to check for nulls.
というわけで、これがnullチェックを不要にしてくれるOptionだったよ。
There is another special pseudo collection, so to speak, that we call try.
もう一つの擬似コレクションがあって、それがTryだ。
And this guards against methods which can throw exceptions.
Tryは例外をスローする可能性のあるメソッドに対して防御してくれるんだ。
So let me define an unsafe method.
安全でないメソッドを定義してみよう。
I'm going to call this method which can throw exception.
名前はmethodWhichCanThrowExceptionにする。
I'm declaring that this method can return a string, but in fact, I can throw new runtime exception.
戻り値はStringと宣言するけど、実際にはnew RuntimeExceptionをスローするんだ。
Exceptions are really bad for JVM programs like Scala programs or Java programs
例外はScalaやJavaみたいなJVMプログラムにとって本当に厄介で、
because they can interrupt or essentially break everything.
処理を中断させたり、全部壊したりする可能性があるからね。
And so we need to guard against exceptions with what you saw earlier with try catches.
だから、前にやったようにtry-catchで例外に対して防御する必要がある。
So normally we would say try.
普通はtryって書いて、
And then inside the try block, we would say method which can throw exception.
tryブロックの中にmethodWhichCanThrowExceptionを入れる。
And then we would catch all the exceptions that we like.
そして好きな例外をcatchする。
So we can have case E call an exception, and then we would defend against this evil exception.
case e: Exceptionみたいに書いて、この悪い例外に対処するわけだ。
Adding many layers of this will lead to very defensive code, adding complexity to large code bases and making code almost unreadable.
でもこれを何層にも重ねると、防御的なコードだらけになって、大きなコードベースが複雑になり、ほとんど読めなくなるんだよね。
And this is why Scala uses the try so-called pseudo collection in the following way.
だからScalaでは、Tryという擬似コレクションを次のように使うんだ。
Let me define a try as try with a capital T.
大文字のTでTryを定義しよう。
This is from Scalutil.
scala.utilにあるやつだよ。
And try can wrap something that can throw an exception.
Tryは例外をスローする可能性のあるものをラップできる。
So method which can throw exception.
つまりmethodWhichCanThrowExceptionをラップする。
And this is a try object containing either a string, if the method went correctly, or it can contain the exception that was thrown.
これはTryオブジェクトで、メソッドが正常に動作すればStringを含み、例外がスローされればその例外を含むんだ。
So try will essentially swallow the exception that might be thrown, and wrap it in a regular value.
つまりTryは、スローされるかもしれない例外を飲み込んで、普通の値としてラップしてくれるんだ。
So a try is a "collection" with either a value if the code went well, or an exception if the code threw one.
Tryは「コレクション」で、コードがうまくいけば値を持ち、例外がスローされればその例外を持つんだ。
And you can pattern match a try object in much the same way as we did with an option.
そしてTryオブジェクトも、Optionと同じようにpattern matchできるよ。
For example, let's call this another string processing as a try match.
例えばanotherStringProcessingとして、aTry matchと書こう。
And we can match against the two subtypes of try, which are success.
Tryの2つのサブタイプに対してマッチできる。まずSuccess。
So we have success, then I need to import from ScalaUtil containing a valid value.
scala.utilからインポートが必要だけど、Successは有効な値を含むんだ。
And I can say, I have obtained a valid string.
で、「I have obtained a valid string」って書いて、
And I can inject the valid value inside.
有効な値をその中に埋め込むことができる。
Or we can have a case for failure.
あるいはFailureのcaseも書ける。
And I need to import failure from ScalaUtil.
scala.utilからFailureもインポートが必要だよ。
And the failure will contain an exception.
Failureは例外を含んでいる。
And we can process that exception around.
その例外を処理できるんだ。
We can log it.
ログに記録してもいいし、
We can do whatever you want.
好きなことができる。
So I have obtained an exception.
「I have obtained an exception」って書いて、
And I can inject that inside.
例外をその中に埋め込めるよ。
So we use tries to avoid defensiveness with try catches.
というわけで、try-catchによる防御的なコードを避けるためにTryを使うんだ。
Instead, we process tries like we would on normal values.
代わりに、Tryを普通の値と同じように処理できる。
The try object and the option object can be processed like we did with collections.
TryオブジェクトとOptionオブジェクトは、コレクションと同じように処理できるんだ。
So both try and option have the map, flat map, and filter compositional functions,
TryとOptionの両方にmap、flatMap、filterという合成用の関数があって、
alongside some others that I'm not going to talk about in this video.
他にもあるけど、この動画では触れないよ。
So I'm actually going to add some green comments here.
じゃあ、ここにセクション分けのコメントを入れておこう。
So that you can separate the sections much more easily.
セクションが見分けやすくなるようにね。
So I'm going to add some documentation comments here.
ドキュメントコメントを追加するよ。
So we have lazy evaluation and pseudo collections.
遅延評価と擬似コレクションだね。
Let me tell you another thing.
もう一つ教えるよ。
Let me tell you how to evaluate something on another thread.
別のスレッドで何かを評価する方法を見せよう。
In other words, asynchronous programming.
つまり、非同期プログラミングだね。
This is done with another quote unquote pseudo collection known as a future.
これもまた、カギ括弧付きの「擬似コレクション」で、Futureっていうんだ。
So let me define a val called a future.
futureっていうvalを定義しよう。
As future, which I will import from ScalaConcurrent.
scala.concurrentからFutureをインポートするよ。
So I'm going to double click here.
ここをダブルクリックして。
And to the constructor of future, I'm going to pass a code block.
Futureのコンストラクタにコードブロックを渡すんだ。
So this expression will be actually evaluated on another thread.
この式は実際に別のスレッドで評価されるよ。
Let's say print line loading with suspension points.
println("loading...")って書こう。三点リーダー付きでね。
Then let's do a thread sleep.
そしてThread.sleepを呼ぶ。
With 1000 milliseconds.
1000ミリ秒で。
This call is very familiar for you Java programmers.
このメソッドはJavaプログラマーにはおなじみだよね。
Thread.sleep will actually block the running thread by one second.
Thread.sleepは実行中のスレッドを1秒間ブロックするんだ。
So 1000 milliseconds.
つまり1000ミリ秒。
Then let me print line.
そしてprintlnで、
I have computed a value.
「I have computed a value」と出力して、
And let me return the value.
値を返すようにしよう。
Let's say 67.
例えば67にしよう。
Now, in order to run a future, we will need to import an execution context, which I'm going to import above.
Futureを実行するには、ExecutionContextをインポートする必要があるんだ。上の方でインポートするよ。
So right at the very top of the file, I'm going to import the following.
ファイルの一番上にこれをインポートする。
Scala.concurrent.executionContext with a capital E.
scala.concurrent.ExecutionContext、大文字のEでね。
So executionContext.implicits with a capital I.
ExecutionContext.Implicits、大文字のIで。
And then global.
そしてglobal。
I'm going to discuss implicits later in this video, shortly.
implicitについてはこの動画の後半で話すよ。
So in a couple of minutes.
あと数分でね。
Now, if you import this value, then notice that the compiler is now happy that this global value is available to run this future.
この値をインポートすると、コンパイラはこのglobal値が利用可能になったことで、Futureを実行できるようになるんだ。
is the equivalent of a thread pull.
これはスレッドプールと同等のものだよ。
That is a collection of threads on which we can schedule the evaluation of this expression.
つまり、この式の評価をスケジュールできるスレッドのコレクションなんだ。
So if we run this application, we will see both the I'm so very lazy and loading.
アプリケーションを実行すると、「I am so very lazy」と「loading」の両方が表示されるよ。
But the main thread of the JVM, the main thread of the application, finished before this future had the chance to evaluate.
でもJVMのメインスレッド、つまりアプリケーションのメインスレッドが、Futureの評価が終わる前に終了しちゃったんだ。
That's a proof that this future, the block that I put here under the constructor of the future, was actually evaluated on another thread.
これは、Futureのコンストラクタに渡したブロックが、実際に別のスレッドで評価された証拠だよ。
If I do thread sleep for two seconds here under the main JVM thread, the main application thread, then this future will also have the chance to evaluate.
メインJVMスレッド、メインアプリケーションスレッドの下でThread.sleepを2秒入れれば、Futureも評価が完了する時間ができる。
Look at that, I have computed a value.
ほら、「I have computed a value」が表示されたね。
Now, two things to mention here about the future.
さて、Futureについて2つ触れておきたいことがある。
Notice the syntax.
まず構文に注目してほしい。
The future is actually future.apply, as you have seen in other instances throughout the rest of this mini-course.
Futureは実はFuture.applyなんだ。このミニコースの他の場面でも見てきたよね。
Now, in real-life code bases, we actually omit the parentheses over here, because this block will be passed as an argument to the future.apply method.
実際のコードベースでは、ここの括弧は省略するんだ。このブロックがFuture.applyメソッドの引数として渡されるからね。
So that was one thing.
これが1つ目。
The second thing is that the future is a quote-unquote collection.
2つ目は、Futureもカギ括弧付きの「コレクション」だってこと。
So you can think of a future as a collection which contains a value when it's evaluated.
Futureは、評価が完了したときに値を含むコレクションだと思えばいいよ。
So at the point when this code block is evaluated, this quote-unquote collection will actually contain a value.
つまり、このコードブロックが評価された時点で、この「コレクション」に実際に値が入るんだ。
Until then, it does not contain any value.
それまでは、値は入っていない。
But a future is composable with map, flat map, and filter.
でもFutureはmap、flatMap、filterで合成できるんだ。
In much the same way as we did with the other collections and pseudo-collections in this application.
他のコレクションや擬似コレクションでやったのとまったく同じようにね。
So we talked about pseudo-collections that we named in between air quotes in very theoretical terms.
というわけで、カギ括弧付きで「擬似コレクション」って呼んだものについて、かなり理論的な話をしてきたね。
The future, try, and option types are called monads in functional programming.
Future、Try、Optionは、関数型プログラミングではモナドと呼ばれているんだ。
Monads are a very touchy subject in functional programming because they are very, very, very, very, quite very abstract and very hard to explain.
モナドは関数型プログラミングでかなりデリケートな話題で、ものすごーく抽象的で説明するのがめちゃくちゃ難しいんだよ。
Some people have tried explaining what monads are, but for now, just don't think about it.
モナドを説明しようとした人もいるけど、今は気にしなくて大丈夫。
Think of future try and option as some sort of a collection.
Future、Try、Optionはコレクションの一種だと思っておいてね。
Now, the final thing that I'm going to show you in this video is implicits.
さて、この動画で最後に見せるのはimplicitだよ。
Implicits are one of the most powerful features of the Skala compiler because they allow for some magic that you wouldn't have thought possible.
implicitはScalaコンパイラの中で最も強力な機能の一つで、思いもよらない魔法のようなことができるんだ。
There are two common use cases for using implicits.
implicitの一般的なユースケースは2つある。
Use case number one is implicit arguments.
ユースケースその1は、implicit引数だ。
So if I define a method with implicit args and this takes an implicit, this is a keyword, implicit value.
aMethodWithImplicitArgsっていうメソッドを定義して、implicitキーワードを使った引数を取るようにする。
Let's call this implicit arg as an int and returns, let's say, arg plus one.
implicitArgをInt型にして、戻り値はarg + 1にしよう。
Then if I define an implicit val, let's call this my implicit int as equal, let's say, 46, then I can print line, for example, a method with implicit args without passing any arguments.
次にimplicit valとしてmyImplicitIntを46と定義すると、println(aMethodWithImplicitArgs)って引数なしで呼べるんだ。
That is because the compiler figures out that the method takes an implicit argument and tries to find a value of type int that it can inject here as an argument.
なぜかというと、コンパイラがこのメソッドにimplicit引数があることを理解して、引数として注入できるInt型の値を探すからなんだ。
So it actually does a method with implicit arguments with my implicit int, which is 46, and this method will return 47.
つまり実際にはaMethodWithImplicitArgs(myImplicitInt)が呼ばれて、46が渡されるから、このメソッドは47を返すんだ。
Good.
いいね。
So this was the first use case with implicit arguments.
これがimplicit引数の最初のユースケースだった。
I think this is pretty sensible.
まあ割と納得しやすいよね。
The second use case, which is much more magical, is implicit conversions.
2つ目のユースケースはもっと魔法っぽくて、暗黙の型変換（implicit conversions）だ。
So let me give you an example.
例を見せるね。
Usually we do implicit conversions to add methods to existing types over which we don't have any control over the code.
暗黙の型変換は普通、自分がコードを変更できない既存の型にメソッドを追加するために使うんだ。
So I'm going to define an implicit class.
implicit classを定義するよ。
So an implicit class that I'm going to call my rich integer, which takes as constructor arguments an int, let's call this n.
MyRichIntegerっていうimplicit classで、コンストラクタ引数としてIntのnを取る。
And this class has a method is even, which takes no arguments.
このクラスにはisEvenっていう引数なしのメソッドがある。
And the return value of this function is whether n mod 2 is equal to zero.
この関数の戻り値は、n % 2 == 0かどうかだ。
All right.
よし。
So what I've done here is I've wrapped an integer into a class that I called my rich integer.
つまりここでやったのは、整数をMyRichIntegerっていうクラスでラップしたってことだね。
And this my rich integer has a single method called is even, which returns true if this wrapped int is actually even.
このMyRichIntegerにはisEvenっていうメソッドがあって、ラップされたIntが偶数ならtrueを返す。
So n mod 2 is equal to zero.
n % 2 == 0ってことだね。
Now, watch what I'm writing.
さあ、これから書くことに注目してね。
I can say the number 23 dot is even in this case, even though the is even method does not belong to the int class.
23.isEvenって書けるんだ。isEvenメソッドはInt型に属してないのにね。
So if I remove the implicit modifier for this class, notice that this code turns red because the method is not available for the int type.
このクラスからimplicit修飾子を外すと、Int型にこのメソッドがないからコードが赤くなるんだ。
But if I do implicit class my rich integer, the compiler is smart enough to figure out, okay, this code does not normally compile.
でもimplicit class MyRichIntegerにすると、コンパイラが賢く判断してくれる。「あれ、このコードは普通にはコンパイルできないぞ。
Let me find an implicit wrapper over this value over here, which is an int.
この値、つまりIntに対するimplicitなラッパーを探してみよう」ってね。
Maybe I can find one and maybe just maybe that class has an is even method.
「もしかしたら見つかるかもしれないし、もしかしたらそのクラスにisEvenメソッドがあるかもしれない」って。
So the compiler is kind enough to do new my rich integer with the number 23 and then call the is even method on that.
コンパイラが親切にもnew MyRichInteger(23)を作って、それに対してisEvenメソッドを呼んでくれるんだ。
And this is pretty magical because it makes Scala an incredibly expressive language, but this is also dangerous.
これはかなり魔法的で、Scalaを信じられないほど表現力豊かな言語にしてるんだけど、危険でもあるんだ。
So use implicit with very, very much care.
だからimplicitはものすごく慎重に使ってね。
All right, so the Scala at Lightspeed mini course has come to an end.
さあ、これでScala at Lightspeedのミニコースは終わりだよ。
I'm Daniel for Rock the JVM and I hope this was useful and fun.
Rock the JVMのDanielでした。役に立って楽しかったら嬉しいな。
I will be waiting for you in the other Rock the JVM courses.
他のRock the JVMのコースでもお待ちしてるよ。
And until next time, thank you for watching.
それではまた次回、見てくれてありがとう。
I'm Daniel for Rock the JVM.
Rock the JVMのDanielでした。